Steven Hobbs 16620 San Benito PI Morgan Hill CA 95037 cell:(408) 782-4204 mail.shobbs@gmail.com

SUMMARY

As a graduate from the University of California Santa Cruz (UCSC), I will apply all the knowledge gained from my experiences and contacts in order to leave a warm and lasting impression on the clientele. I would be right at home among any IT staff or application developers. I have conducted research at UCSC and Caltech through the Southern California Bioinformatics Institute and MARC/MBRS programs. I also received professional training in presenting scientific documents and reports.

EXPERIENCE

DMV Motor Vehicle Representative | SANTA CLARA, CA February 2014 - April 2018

- Processed vehicle registration, driver license, and occupational license applications.
- Helped examiners with vehicle verification, testing visuals and knowledge examinations.
- conduct attendance, inventory and other human resource related reports
- Communicated within the department via pc, phone and fax.
- review of possible fraudulent documents for AB 60 applicants, Driver suspensions and reinstatement, Admin per Se, commercial licensing.
- Processed reports involving liens, salvage or dealer transactions.

CalTEACH BIOLOGY INTERN | APTOS, CA

September 2009 - December 2010

- Assisted Students and Teachers at a High School.
- Attended a weekly seminar discussing classroom management and improving student interactions.
- Bi-weekly I assisted teaching in Aptos High School in a Biology Classroom.
- Kept an hourly written journal of each session and each interaction.

SUBJECT TUTOR COMPUTER NETWORKS | SANTA CRUZ, CA January 2010 - March 2010

 Tutored Students in Computer Networks, in a one on one or small group setting. Steven Hobbs 16620 San Benito Pl Morgan Hill CA 95037 cell:(408) 782-4204

mail.shobbs@gmail.com

 Addressed issues arising in network architecture models and conceptual layers, (physical to the application layer), characteristics of transmission media; switching techniques (packet switching, circuit switching), medium access control (MAC) protocols, local area networks; error-control strategies and link-level protocols; routing algorithms for bridges and routers; congestion control mechanisms; transport protocols; QoS, application of concepts to practical wireless and wireline networks.

MARC/MBRS/CAMP RESEARCH FELLOW | SANTA CRUZ, CA September 2007 - September 2009

- While a member of research fellowship I attended a weekly seminar presenting undergraduate research from various fields. I was guided in producing lab reports and presenting scientific findings to a general audience.
- Conducted research in Chemistry, Biology, Immunology, Biochemistry, Neurobiology, Laboratories.
- My main research consisted of applying backpropagation to the neural networks used to predict protein structure as part of a bioinformatics lab.

SOCAL BSI UNDERGRADUATE RESEARCHER | LOS ANGELES, CA June 2007 - September 2007

- Interned at California State University LA in a Bioinformatics Lab.
- Trained in mathematical models of statistical learning, Python coding, bioethics, tasked to write a database application for sharing Developmental Biology data.

Computer Science Lab Tutor/TA UCSC | SANTA CRUZ, CA September 2006 - November 2006

- Attended the Computer Lab course offered to entry level students learning Computer Programming skills.
- Assisted students troubleshoot programing assignments in C,Java and basic Unix commands at their workstation.
- Instructed students in more advanced topics like data structures and data parsing.
- Grade and correct submitted electronic assignments and test.

Steven Hobbs 16620 San Benito PI Morgan Hill CA 95037 cell:(408) 782-4204 mail.shobbs@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science Degree in Bioinformatics. 2005-2010 University of California Santa Cruz, Santa Cruz, CA

SKILLS

Computer Science Courses / Certifications:

Data Structures, Object Oriented, Java SWING GUI, Machine Learning Languages: Java, Ansi C, C++, Perl, Python, SQL, Matlab, R, POWERSHELL Operating Systems: UNIX,LINUX,WINDOWS,OSX,ANDROID,IOS,

PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES

- Rebecca Anderson, Subject Tutor Computer Networks, Phone: 1(831)459-1902
- Patrick Kent, Calteach Intern High School Biology Assistant Teacher, Phone: 1(831)459-1929
- Yulianna Ortega, MARC/MBRS student researcher, Phone: 1(831)459-3761
- Ronnie Cheng, Research Assistant Intern Sea Urchin Lab, Phone: (323) 343-2494,
- Charlie McDowell, Lab Tutor/Grader, Jack Baskin School of Engineering, Phone: 1(831) 459-4772
- Cindy Falcone, Motor Vehicle Representative DMV Santa Clara/Region 2, Phone: 1(408) 2771313